RENATA REINARTZ

Full Stack Developer

www.linkedin.com/in/renata1026

SUMMARY

Accomplished full-stack developer with two years of freelance web development experience. Proficient in React and RESTful APIs, recognized for strong analytical capabilities and effective communication. Additionally, a certified hatha yoga teacher, bringing a holistic perspective to personal well-being and professional growth.

TECH STACK

HTML	CSS	SASS	
JavaScript		eact	Expres
Netlify	Render		Rest APIs
Prisma	GIT	Node	
Cockroad	chDB	Githu	ıp

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive **Bootcamp**

Juno College of Technology

= 09/2022 - 02/2023

Chartered Professional Accountant

Chartered Professional Accountants of Canada

= 06/2015 - 06/2015

Bachelor of Management: Advanced Accounting

Univeristy of Lethbridge

CERTIFICATION

Agile Scrum and Project Management of Software **Products**

Udemy 2023

RYT 200 & RYT 300

Certified Yoga Teacher

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Stay Calm Virtual Services

- ## 09/2021 Present
- Specializing in front-end development and creating a unique digital footprint leveraging human-centered design principles for clients across various industries which has led to increased traffic between 20 - 40% for clients.

Remote

- Clients:
- Dr. Graham Lea, Internal Medicine Clinic
- [https://drgrahamlea.com]
- The Ambitious Assistant [https://theambitiousassistant.com]
- Lift Your Vibe [https://www.liftyourvibe.ca]

Software Engineering Apprentice

Hackmyhead

m 07/2023 - 10/2023

Remote

During my Engineering and Full-stack Web Development apprenticeship at Hackmyhead, I dedicated over 192 hours to collaborative development. I actively participated in crafting dynamic full stack applications using technologies like React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, Node, Prisma, Git, and GitHub.

Freelance Developer

Easy-Evergreen

m 06/2022 - 10/2022

Remote

- Revamped client sites for Easy-Evergreen based on customer requirements and functionality required such as dynamic popups and integrated webforms. Integrated websites with Google Analytics and email marketing systems to streamline digital operations and provide reporting capabilities and improve SEO ranking
- Thrivewell Solutions [https://thrivewellsolutions.com]
- Catherine Arkema [https://catherinearkema.com]

Online English Teacher and Evaluator

Whales English

= 2018 - 2022

Remote

Instructed ESL students in one-to-one and one-to-ten virtual settings using Zoom. Promoted to an evaluator reviewed playback of over 40 teachers monthly (1000 + teachers in total) and wrote evaluation reports.

Accounting Manager

Pacekids Programs

2014 - 2018

Calgary, AB

- Converted the company's software to QuickBooks Pro and implemented an accrual-based accounting system with monthly cutoffs which led to 98% more accurate reporting.
- Created a monthly cash flow report and financial package for the board of directors which led to better spending practices and a more balanced budget.

Previous positions included Senior Financial Analyst, Accountant, and Corporate Reporting Analyst at multinational companies.

WestJet, Finning International

- **=** 2008 2013
- Directed a team of five, providing mentorship and
- Created billion-dollar monthly forecast reports using Khalix Longview, a financial reporting and performance management software integrated with Excel, and monthly reports for the CFO press conferences, ensuring accuracy and timeliness for quarterly and annual shareholder meetings.

PROJECTS

Astro Planner

iii 10/2023 - 10/2023

https://astro-planner.netlify.app

[https://github.com/renata1026/astroplanner-client]

In my role as project manager and developer for the Astro Planner Travel App, I led React front-end development, building reusable login and register components with authentication. I also played a crucial role in the back-end, creating endpoints and API documentation, utilizing Prisma ORM for database management on Cockroach DB. My multifaceted contributions included mentoring team members and ensuring on-time milestone delivery, highlighting my versatile skills and leadership.

Reddit Clone

09/2023 - 09/2023

A https://reddit-clone-site.netlify.app

[https://github.com/renata1026/redditclient]

Developed a full-stack social media application, akin to Reddit, utilizing React for the front end and Prisma with Express for the backend. Cockroach DB hosted the database, ensuring scalability and data integrity. This project highlights my expertise in web development and my ability to create dynamic, user-friendly applications with essential social features.

Makeup4 Life

= 12/2022 - 05/2023

https://makeup4life.netlify.app

[https://github.com/renata1026/makeupecommerce-store]

Crafted a user-centric makeup eCommerce platform featuring customizable products through integration with the Makeup API. Leveraging React, local storage, and SASS, I meticulously designed components, established seamless routing, and implemented a robust cart functionality for an enriched shopping experience.

Podcast Planner

m 02/2023 - 02/2023

https://podcast-walk-planner.netlify.app

[https://github.com/renata1026/podcastplanner]

In the Podcast Planner project, I focused on crafting the user experience and designing selection forms to create a seamless process for users to input walk duration, choose podcast genres, and generate personalized playlists. Using React, Sweet Alerts 2, Axios, and Framer Motion, I contributed to a mobile-first design, ensuring an enjoyable podcast planning experience. Firebase stores playlists, and Listen Notes API generates content.